On March 7, 1907, the English statistician Francis Galton published a paper which illustrated what has come to be known as the “wisdom of crowds” effect.
1907年3月7日，英国统计学家弗朗西斯·高尔顿发表了一篇论文，阐释了后来被称为“群体智慧”效应的现象。
The estimation experiment he conducted showed that in some cases, the average of a large number of independent estimates could be quite accurate.
他所做的估算实验表明，在某些情况下，大量独立估计的平均值可以相当准确。
This effect capitalizes on the fact that when people make errors, those errors aren’t always the same.
这一效应利用了这样一个事实：人们出错时，误差并不总是相同的。
Some people will tend to overestimate, and some to underestimate.
有些人往往会高估，有些人则往往会低估。
When enough of these errors are averaged together, they cancel each other out, resulting in a more accurate estimate.
把足够多的这类误差平均起来时，它们就会相互抵消，从而得出更准确的估计。
If people are similar and tend to make the same errors, then their errors won’t cancel each other out.
如果人们彼此相似、往往犯同样的错误，那么他们的误差就不会相互抵消。
In more technical terms, the wisdom of crowds requires that people’s estimates be independent.
用更专业的话来说，群体智慧要求人们的估计是相互独立的。
If, for whatever reasons, people’s errors become correlated or dependent, the accuracy of the estimate will go down.
无论出于什么原因，只要人们的误差变得相互关联或相互依赖，估计的准确度就会下降。
But a new study led by Joaquin Navajas offered an interesting twist on this classic phenomenon.
但华金·纳瓦哈斯主导的一项新研究为这一经典现象带来了一个有趣的新转折。
The key finding of the study was that when crowds were further divided into smaller groups that were allowed to have a discussion, the averages from these groups were more accurate than those from an equal number of independent individuals.
这项研究的关键发现是：如果把人群进一步分成可以进行讨论的小组，这些小组得出的平均值就比同等数量的独立个人得出的平均值更准确。
For instance, the average obtained from the estimates of four discussion groups of five was significantly more accurate than the average obtained from 20 independent individuals.
例如，由4个5人讨论小组的估计得出的平均值，明显比由20个独立个人得出的平均值更准确。
In a follow-up study with 100 university students, the researchers tried to get a better sense of what the group members actually did in their discussion.
在一项有100名大学生参与的后续研究中，研究人员试图更清楚地了解小组成员在讨论中实际做了什么。
Did they tend to go with those most confident about their estimates?
他们是否往往会听从那些对自己的估计最有把握的人？
Did they follow those least willing to change their minds?
他们是否会听从那些最不愿意改变主意的人？
This happened some of the time, but it wasn’t the dominant response.
这种情况有时确实发生，但并不是主要的反应。
Most frequently, the groups reported that they “shared arguments and reasoned together”.
各小组最常反映的是，他们“交流了论据，并一起进行推理”。
Somehow, these arguments and this reasoning resulted in a global reduction in error.
不知何故，这些论据和推理使误差在整体上减少了。
Although the studies led by Navajas have limitations and many questions remain, the potential implications for group discussion and decision-making are enormous.
尽管纳瓦哈斯主导的这些研究存在局限，许多问题也仍未解决，但它们对群体讨论和决策的潜在影响是巨大的。